

Queens, NY

□ (+1) 347-430-3398 | Machristianmsakai@gmail.com | Onchristiansakai | Christiansakai | Ch

Summary ____

Software Engineer with around 3 years of experience specializing in fullstack web development. Interests in web development, programming languages, compilers, systems development, data, and functional programming. Play guitar, bass and sing to keep myself creative, practice karate to keep myself healthy.

Skills

Proficient JavaScript/TypeScript, HTML & CSS, Angular, React, Redux, NodeJS, MongoDB, Webpack, Grunt, Gulp, Git

Knowledgeable Elixir, Phoenix, Ecto, PostgreSQL, Sass, Haskell, Elm, ŁTFX, AWS, Docker, D3

Basic C, C++, Java, Lisp

Work Experience _____

IrisVR Inc.

New York City

SOFTWARE ENGINEER CONSULTANT Oct. 2016 - PRESENT

- · Implemented efficient build system on company's front end and desktop app development environment using Webpack
- · Designed failure-point handling to handle disconnections between several NodeJS backend services gracefully
- Migrated company's MongoDB and AWS Redshift database changes with ensured consistency
- · Built an offline open source analytics caching library to preserve analytics in case of unavailable connection for company's desktop app
- Worked on various features on company's front end and desktop app

FactorSpot Maryland

SOFTWARE ENGINEER CONSULTANT

VARIOUS CONTRACT DATES

- Designed security policy over company's Firebase data
- Integrated Intuit's Quickbook API to company's backend
- Built Bobtail fullstack web app using Elixir and Phoenix

Ninthbeat Inc.

New York City

Co-Founder & Software Engineer

Mar. 2015 - Dec. 2015

- Built company's web app using MEAN stack
- Built company's smartphone app using Ionic

Fullstack Academy New York City

TEACHING FELLOW Jul. 2014 - Feb. 2015

- · Assisted instructors on lecture
- Designed a Grunt workshop for students
- Assisted and reviewed student projects
- Built company's internal social media platform web app

Education _

Queens College Flushing, NY

M.A. IN COMPUTER SCIENCE 2016 - 2018

Alliance Theological Seminary Manhattan, NY

M.Div. in Theological Studies 2010 - 2013

Bina Nusantara University

Jakarta, Indonesia

B.Eng. in Industrial Engineering 2004 - 2008

April 26, 2018 Christian Sakai · Résumé